<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fishy&#39;s Notebook</title>
    <link>https://fishysnotebook.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Fishy&#39;s Notebook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fishysnotebook.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Spring 2022 Projects</title>
      <link>https://fishysnotebook.com/posts/202203_newmrgprojects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fishysnotebook.com/posts/202203_newmrgprojects/</guid>
      <description>Marine Robotics Group At the moment, I am leading two electrical projects in the Marine Robotics Group.
The first project is the Nova Motor, a modified Newport Vessels trolling motor which is being controlled with a PWM module that interfaces with a Pi Pico for use with micro-ROS. The second project is the ORCS Comms system, an OrangeRX-based communication system with a failsafe E-stop. I am looking forward to leveraging skills I gained in PCB design and electrical work while working on a prototype DAQ system for the Yellow Jacket Space Program.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crosspost: Towards Easier ROS Setup &amp; Collaboration</title>
      <link>https://fishysnotebook.com/posts/202107_towardseasiercolab/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fishysnotebook.com/posts/202107_towardseasiercolab/</guid>
      <description>Check out my write-up over here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021 RoboBoat Auxiliary Test Vehicle</title>
      <link>https://fishysnotebook.com/posts/202106_auxiliaryasv/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fishysnotebook.com/posts/202106_auxiliaryasv/</guid>
      <description>For the RoboBoat 2021 competition, our team was essentially completely virtual. However, we tried our best to make the most of it. During this project, I experimented with two things:
 Liquid rubber as a waterproof coating for a foamboard hull Bilge pump motors  The foamboard hull was rather limited in displacement, but it got the job done. The liquid rubber held up for the most part, but it did not adhere well to packing tape and would peel easily on the sharp folded corners of the foamboard hull.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2012 Hasbro R2-D2 Dome Controller</title>
      <link>https://fishysnotebook.com/posts/202102_summaryquadrature/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fishysnotebook.com/posts/202102_summaryquadrature/</guid>
      <description>In late high school, I decided to disassemble my old toy R2-D2 with the intent of making an even better robot. That robot is still a work in progress, and I&amp;rsquo;ve learned a lot since then. In the meantime, I have at least figured out how to control the planetary gear system that allows the dome to rotate. It utilizes a quadrature encoder incorporating two pairs of infrared blasters and sensors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Symbolic Chat Systems</title>
      <link>https://fishysnotebook.com/posts/202101_symbolicnotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fishysnotebook.com/posts/202101_symbolicnotes/</guid>
      <description>Symbolic methods Personally, I think GOFAI gets an undue amount of neglect and hate these days. Video games use them, and they can be fairly effective at simulating reasonable intelligent behavior. Not to say there isn&amp;rsquo;t any use with recent techniques, but symbolic systems are just more easily deciphered. Well, at least when they don&amp;rsquo;t explode in complexity, like FSMs do.
Additionally, humans do use symbols, is it so wrong to think that we can use neural and symbolic methods together?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ROS on Fedora Silverblue</title>
      <link>https://fishysnotebook.com/posts/202012_rospod/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fishysnotebook.com/posts/202012_rospod/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve run Gazebo on WSL2 before, albeit sluggishly. One difference between Docker and Podman is apparently the way networks are handled.
podman run -it -e DISPLAY --rm --net=host osrf/ros:melodic-desktop-full bash
podman run --rm -v /tmp/.X11-unix:/tmp/.X11-unix -v /dev/dri:/dev/dri --security-opt=label=type:container_runtime_t -e DISPLAY localhost/xonotic-container xonotic-glx
podman run --rm -v /tmp/.X11-unix:/tmp/.X11-unix -v /dev/dri:/dev/dri --security-opt=label=type:container_runtime_t -e DISPLAY osrf/ros:melodic-desktop-full bash</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Binaries on Silverblue</title>
      <link>https://fishysnotebook.com/posts/202012_silverblue/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fishysnotebook.com/posts/202012_silverblue/</guid>
      <description>Recently I started playing around with Fedora Silverblue 33.
I could not figure out how to install Julia, until I found this article.
So using the method described here, I was able to install both Julia and Hugo onto my system and incorporate them into my PATH without rpm-ostree.
It took a long time for me to run into this on Google, so I&amp;rsquo;m posting it here too, just in case.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crosspost: Running ROS with GUI in Docker using WSL2</title>
      <link>https://fishysnotebook.com/posts/202008_rosguidockerwsl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fishysnotebook.com/posts/202008_rosguidockerwsl/</guid>
      <description>Check out my write-up over here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drone Controller - 2019 Aerohacks</title>
      <link>https://fishysnotebook.com/posts/201902_aerohacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fishysnotebook.com/posts/201902_aerohacks/</guid>
      <description>NOTE: This write-up is from 2022.
Aerohacks 2019 was my first hardware hackathon. It was so much fun. My friends and I built a single-handed drone controller from spare parts. I learned how to prototype with an Arduino. We hooked up the Arduino to a simulation in Processing to demonstrate the control scheme of the controller. Here&amp;rsquo;s a photo of our prototype:
Here&amp;rsquo;s some code from that hackathon which perhaps I&amp;rsquo;ll pick up again one day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Archive</title>
      <link>https://fishysnotebook.com/archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fishysnotebook.com/archives/</guid>
      <description>archives</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search</title>
      <link>https://fishysnotebook.com/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fishysnotebook.com/search/</guid>
      <description>search</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
